innocenceproject.org 2018-06-29

# Privacy Policy - Innocence Project

**Innocence Project Privacy Policy**

The Innocence Project (“The Innocence Project,” “we,” “our,” or “us”) understands that privacy is important to our online visitors to our website.  This Privacy Policy explains how we collect, use, share, and protect your personal information that we collect on our website.  By using our website, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and our [Terms of Use](http://www.innocenceproject.org/legal).

Click on the links below to jump to each section:

**1.             ** **[WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT AND FOR WHAT PURPOSE?](http://www.innocenceproject.org/privacy-policy#one)  
****2.             [HOW WE USE COOKIES AND OTHER TRACKING TECHNOLOGY TO COLLECT INFORMATION](http://www.innocenceproject.org/privacy-policy#two)  
**3.             [SHARING OF YOUR INFORMATION](http://www.innocenceproject.org/privacy-policy#three)**[ ](http://www.innocenceproject.org/privacy-policy#three)  
**4.            [YOUR CHOICES ABOUT YOUR INFORMATION](http://www.innocenceproject.org/privacy-policy#four)**[ ](http://www.innocenceproject.org/privacy-policy#four)  
**5.             [HOW WE STORE AND PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION](http://www.innocenceproject.org/privacy-policy#five)**[ ](http://www.innocenceproject.org/privacy-policy#five)  
**6.             [CHILDREN’S PRIVACY](http://www.innocenceproject.org/privacy-policy#six)**[ ](http://www.innocenceproject.org/privacy-policy#six)  
******7.             [LINKS TO OTHER WEB SITES AND SERVICES](http://www.innocenceproject.org/privacy-policy#seven)  
**8.             [HOW TO CONTACT US](http://www.innocenceproject.org/privacy-policy#eight)**[ ](http://www.innocenceproject.org/privacy-policy#eight)  
**9.             [CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY](http://www.innocenceproject.org/privacy-policy#nine)**[ ](http://www.innocenceproject.org/privacy-policy#nine)****

**1.** **WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT AND FOR WHAT PURPOSE?  **

The categories of information we collect can include:

**Information you provide to us directly:  ** We may collect personal information such as your first and last name, phone number, zip code, billing information, and e-mail address when you sign up for our mailing list, volunteer with us or make a donation.  We may combine this information with information collected from third party sources, such as third parties we partner with to provide our legal services.

  * **Information we collect from social networks:**   We may receive information about you when you interact with our site through various social media, for example, by logging in through or liking us on Facebook or following us on Twitter.  The data we receive is dependent upon your privacy settings with the social network.  You should always review, and if necessary, adjust your privacy settings on third-party websites and services before linking or connecting them to the Innocence Project website.

We use this information to operate, maintain, and enhance our organization and our services.  We may use this information to communicate with you, such as to send you email messages, newsletters, and to follow up with you to offer information about the Innocence Project.  We may also send you service-related emails or messages (e.g., account verification, transactional communications, change or updates to features of the service, technical, and security notices). For more information about your communication preferences, see “Your Choices Regarding Your Information” below.

**2. HOW WE USE COOKIES AND OTHER TRACKING TECHNOLOGY TO COLLECT INFORMATION.**

We and our third party partners may automatically collect certain types of usage information when you visit our website or use our Service.  For instance, when you visit our website, we may send one or more cookies—a small text file containing a string of alphanumeric characters—to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser and lets us help you log in faster and enhance your navigation through the site.  A cookie may also convey information to us about how you use our website (e.g., the pages you view, the links you click, how frequently you access the Service, and other actions you take on the Service), and allow us to track your usage of our website over time.  We may collect log file information about your browser or mobile device each time you access the Service.  Log file information may include anonymous information such as your web request, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, information about your mobile device, referring / exit pages and URLs, number of clicks, and how you interact with links on the Service, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, and other such information. We may employ clear gifs (also known as web beacons) which are used to anonymously track the online usage patterns of our Users.  In addition, we may also use clear gifs in HTML-based emails sent to our users to track which emails are opened and which links are clicked by recipients.  The information allows for more accurate reporting and improvement of our website.  We may collect analytics data, or use third-party analytics tools, to help us measure traffic and usage trends for our website.  These tools collect information sent by your browser or mobile device, including the pages you visit, your use of third party applications, and other information that assists us in analyzing and improving our website and services.  Although we do our best to honor the privacy preferences of our Users, we are not able to respond to Do Not Track signals from your browser at this time, as we believe that there is no consistent industry standard for how to respond to Do Not Track browser settings.

When you access our Service by or through a mobile device, we may receive or collect and store a unique identification number associated with your device (“Device ID”), mobile carrier, device type and manufacturer, and phone number.

We may use the data collected through cookies, log file, device identifiers, location data, and clear gifs to:  (a) remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the site; (b) provide custom, personalized content and information, including advertising; (c) provide and monitor the effectiveness of our Service; (d) monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors, traffic, usage, and demographic patterns on our website and our Service; (e) diagnose or fix technology problems; and (f) otherwise to plan for and enhance our service.

**Third Party Tracking and Online Advertising** **:**   We may permit third party ad networks, social media companies, and other third party services, such as YouTube to collect information about browsing behavior from visitors to our website through cookies, social plug-ins, or other tracking technology.  We may permit third party online advertising networks to collect information about your use of our websites over time so that they may play or display ads that may be relevant to your interests on our Service as well as on other websites or services.  Typically, the information is collected through cookies or similar tracking technologies.  The only way to completely “opt out” of the collection of any information through cookies or other tracking technology is to actively manage the settings on your browser or mobile device.  Please refer to your browser’s or mobile device’s technical information for instructions on how to delete and disable cookies, and other tracking/recording tools.  (To learn more about cookies, clear gifs/web beacons, and related technologies and how you may opt-out of some of this tracking, you may wish to visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) and/or the Network Advertising Initiative’s online resources, at [http://www.networkadvertising.org](https://www.networkadvertising.org/)).  Depending on your mobile device, you may not be able to control tracking technologies through settings.  If you have any questions about opting out of the collection of cookies and other tracking/recording tools, you can contact us directly at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#ed84838b82ad848383828e88838e889d9f8287888e99c3829f8ad29e988f87888e99d0b985849f89c8dfddbd8c9f9994c8dfddb99f8c8e8684838ac8dfdd8c8389c8dfdda28381848388c8dfddac899b889f99849e84838a).

**3\. SHARING OF YOUR INFORMATION**

We may share your personal information in the instances described below.  For further information on your choices regarding your information, see the “Your Choices About Your Information” section below.

We may share your personal information with:

  * Other organizations within the Innocence Network;
  * Third-party vendors and other service providers that perform services on our behalf, as needed to carry out their work for us, which may include identifying and serving targeted advertisements, providing mailing services, providing tax and accounting services, payment processing, web hosting, or providing analytic services;
  * Third parties who partner with us to help provide our services, such as legal organizations and student groups;
  * The public when you provide feedback or user content on our site. For example, if you post user content on our blog or comment on our social media sites, your information, such as your first name, last initial, state of residence, and your comments, may be displayed on our website or in our newsletter or other promotional materials provided by the Innocence Project);
  * Other parties in connection with a company transaction, such as a merger, sale of company assets or shares, reorganization, financing, change of control or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by another company or third party, or in the event of a bankruptcy or related or similar proceedings; and
  * Third parties as required by law or subpoena or if we reasonably believe that such action is necessary to (a) comply with the law and the reasonable requests of law enforcement; (b) to enforce our [Terms of Use](http://www.innocenceproject.org/legal) or to protect the security or integrity of our Service; and/or (c) to exercise or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of the Innocence Project, our Users, or others.

We may also aggregate or otherwise strip data of all personally identifying characteristics and may share that aggregated, anonymized data with third parties.

**4\. YOUR CHOICES ABOUT YOUR INFORMATION**

**How to control your communications preferences** :  You can stop receiving promotional email communications from us by clicking on the “unsubscribe link” provided in such communications.  We make every effort to promptly process all unsubscribe requests.  You may not opt out of service-related communications (e.g., account verification, transactional communications, changes/updates to features of the Service, technical and security notices).

**Modifying or deleting your information:  **If you have any questions about reviewing, modifying, or deleting your information, or if you want to remove your name or comments from our website or publicly displayed content, you can contact us directly at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#4c25222a230c252222232f29222f293c3e2326292f3862233e2b733f392e26292f38711c3e253a2d2f35697e7c1c2320252f35).  We may not be able to modify or delete your information in all circumstances, such as if it has been copied, or commented on by a third party or third party service or if federal or state law requires that we maintain certain information for our records.

**5\. HOW WE STORE AND PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION**

**Storage and Processing** :  Your information collected through our website may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which the Innocence Project or its affiliates or service providers maintain facilities.  If you are located in the European Union or other regions with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, please note that we may transfer information, including personal information, to a country and jurisdiction that does not have the same data protection laws as your jurisdiction, and you consent to the transfer of information to the U.S. or any other country in which the Innocence Project or its parent, subsidiaries, affiliates, or service providers maintain facilities and the use and disclosure of information about you as described in this Privacy Policy.

**Keeping your information safe** :  The Innocence Project cares about the security of your information and uses commercially reasonable physical, administrative, and technological safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of all information collected through our website.  However, no security system is impenetrable and we cannot guarantee the security of our systems 100%.  In the event that any information under our control is compromised as a result of a breach of security, the Innocence Project will take reasonable steps to investigate the situation and, where appropriate, notify those individuals whose information may have been compromised and take other steps, in accordance with any applicable laws and regulations.

**6.            CHILDREN’S PRIVACY**

The Innocence Project does not knowingly collect or solicit any information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register as Users.  In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible.  If you believe that we might have any information from a child under 13, please contact us at [[email protected]oject.org](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#d0b9beb6bf90b9bebebfb3b5beb3b5a0a2bfbab5b3a4febfa2b7efa3a5b2bab5b3a4ed80a2b9a6b1b3a9f5e2e080bfbcb9b3a9).

**7\. LINKS TO OTHER WEB SITES AND SERVICES**

Our website may integrate with or contain links to other third party sites and services.  We are not responsible for the practices employed by third party websites or services embedded in, linked to, or linked from our website and your interactions with any third-party website or service are subject to that third party’s own rules and policies

**8\. HOW TO CONTACT US**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the website, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#e48d8a828ba48d8a8a8b87818a878194968b8e818790ca8b9683db9791868e818790d9b4968d9285879dc1d6d4b48b888d879d).

**9\. CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**

The Innocence Project may modify or update this Privacy Policy from time to time to reflect the changes in our business and practices, and so you should review this page periodically.  When we change the policy in a material manner we will let you know and update the ‘last modified’ date at the bottom of this page.

This privacy policy was last modified on June 1, 2015.
